Tell me one, no, two things
１つ
いえ ２つだけ聞かせてください
Do you believe what you are doing is right?
あなたは自分がしていることが
正しいと信じていますか？
If the nethermost depths of hell,
if Dinebokushiri really does exist,
もし地獄の底
ディネボクシリというものがあるのなら
I imagine that is where I will fall.
私は そこに落ちるだろうな
Is that your answer?
それが答えですか
What is the other thing?
もう１つは？
Your name.
あなたの名を
Hakuoro.
ハクオロ
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼（はね）を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
Gathering Force
おじきー！
Uncle!
今帰ったぜえー！
I'm back.
Hey, there. Why the long face?
よおー しけたツラしてるじゃねえか
So, you done reporting on your little
game of "I'm the General"?
おままごとの報告は済んだのかよ
ふっふふはは
We'll be riding right back out again.
My uncle drives his men hard.
すぐ また出陣よ
おじきも人使いが荒いぜ
Well, I can imagine how you must feel.
まっ あんたの気持も分からねえじゃねえ
戦好きが城の中でおこもりじゃ
鬱憤だってたまらぁな
If someone who loves fighting is
kept inside the castle walls,
I'm sure his frustration must really build up.
But for you guys to have trouble
fighting those bumpkins, well...
それにしても あんたらも
あんな田舎もん達に苦戦するようじゃ
Man, you must be getting soft.
そろそろ焼きが
回ってきたんじゃねえのかあ
うるせえぞ
Shut up, will you? No man should
babble away like that.
男がピーチクパーチク
さえずるんじゃねえ
へっへへへ　へえ
Being with a useless captain must
make you feel really small.
使えねえ大将の所にいちゃ
肩身も狭いわなあ　あう おお！
Wh.. What the hell!?
な 何だ この手は　あっ はあ！
Are you raising your arm against
the great samurai general?
侍大将に手を上げようっていうのか！
So what if I am?
それがどうした
If you like...
何なら…
そ そうだ
I know!
I'll let you into my unit.
あんた 俺の部隊に入れてやる
そうすりゃ戦場で大暴れできる
Then you can go wild on the battlefield.
あんな奴の下にいるよりも
待遇だって よくしてやる
I'll pay you more than what you
get under that other guy.
What was that!?
何だとお！
Stop it, Kurou.
おやめなさい クロウ
General...
大将
Bastard...
てめえ　こんなことして
ただで済むと思うな！ はあ
Don't think you can get away with doing this!
ふん
このことは おじきに報告するからな！
I'll be reporting to my uncle about this!
I can't believe a samurai general
まさか侍大将ともあろう方が
would get upset over a little
joking around like this.
この程度の戯れ事にムキになるとは
せいぜい足元すくわれないように
気をつけな
Just be careful you don't get the rug
pulled out from under you.
I appreciate your words of caution.
ご忠告 感謝します
ふんっ　あのチンピラが侍大将？
That punk is a samurai general!?
足軽にも使えねえ
He wouldn't even make a good foot soldier.
Well now, I wonder about that.
さて どうでしょうか
まさか奴が 器だと？
You don't actually think he's
got talent, do you!?
No...
いいえ
ですが ああいった者は追いつめられると
何をするか分からないものです
But there's no telling what someone
like that will do when cornered.
ふうー　そんなもんですかねえ
Is that right?
Kurou...
クロウ
Our destination has been determined.
我々の行く先が決まりました
おっ　まーってましたぜえ！
It's about time!
Spread your feet.
足を開いて
んっ おう
That's it.
-うんー ん
-あははっ はははは…
話は分かりました
I understand.
We are grateful to have more comrades.
こちらとしても同志が増えるのは
願ってもないこと
However...
ただし
我々の傘下に加わるというならば 指示に
従うことを血判状に誓ってもらうことになる
If you are willing to join us,
you must swear in blood that
you will follow orders.
Do you agree to that?
よろしいか
そりゃ もちろんじゃ
Well, of course we do!
いずれも屈強な猛者ばかり
We are all seasoned veterans.
Please use us.
どうぞ使ってくだされ
だっはは！ 頼もしい限りじゃねえか
They all seem pretty promising, don't they?
ふん　どうだかな
I wonder...
ユタフにエプカラ
それにサンとワッカイの連中と
Yutafu and Epukalla, and San and Wakkai
and their groups...
That many have gathered in just a few days.
数日で これだけ集まったわけだ
Inkalla's random burnings of villages has only
served to hasten things along instead.
インカラの無作為な村焼きが
逆に事態を早めてくれた
Your anger is justified, but...
お前の怒りはもっともだが
I know!
分かっている
ああ ほら　ちゃんと歩いてください
Come on now, please walk properly!
えああ！ とっと
What's all this about?
何だあ？
We caught a guy who was
acting suspiciously.
怪しい男を捕まえた
Eruruu found him.
エルルゥが 見つけただに
No, I...
いえ 私は
I just noticed there was a strange
man climbing the wall.
何か変な人が塀を登っているなあって
And so we've brought him in.
で 連行してきました
Are you one of Inkalla's spies?
インカラの間者か！
Heavens forbid! I just stopped by here
as usual to peddle my wares.
滅相もありませんです
あっしは ただ行商のために
いつもどおり ここに寄っただけでして
But you were climbing the wall.
でも 塀を登って
As I said, I've always been
treated well here,
ですから ここには
よくしてもらっていたんですってばあー
but there was a new guard at the gate,
and he wouldn't let me in.
ところが門番の人が変わっていて
入れてくれないじゃないですかあー
Listen, you, that's...
そりゃあ おめえ…
What!?
えーええー！
You guys captured this castle?
あなた達が占領した？
ああ… あら
ははっ それはおめでとうございます
Well, congratulations!
いよいよ 胡散臭ぇ奴だなあ
He seems even more suspicious now.
Brother, shall I take him out?
兄者 やるか？
ひっ ひいいぃー！
W... Wait a minute!
I didn't mean for this to happen.
ちょ ちょっと待ってください！
私 そんなつもりで…
何なら裸にして
調べてもらっても構いませんからあ
You can strip me of my clothes
and search me, if you like.
Please don't do this to me!
もう勘弁してください！ うう…
兄者 どうするんだ
Brother, what are you going to do?
You are a merchant?
商人か
はい
Yes! I've got whatever it is you might want.
I deal in anything except slaves. Yes!
お頼み頂ければ 人身売買以外は
何でも扱いますです はい
Come on, everyone. Feel free to
check out anything you like.
さあー さあー どうぞ
お手に取って よーくご覧ください
Oh, how unusual.
珍しい
これはマポッティの
This is a Mapottian.
How very knowledgeable.
よくご存じで
エルルゥは薬師だからな
Eruruu is a healer, you see.
Ah, no wonder then.
ほおほお どうりで
In that case, this is a very rare item.
それでは これなんか希少品ですよ
Why that's a...
それは！ はっ
It's the treasure of a sea animal
called the hellapetter.
海に住むヘラペッタという動物の
お宝ですなあ
It works wonders as an aphrodisiac.
精力剤としては効果は抜群です
Your partner won't get a wink of
sleep all night long. Yes!
もう それはそれは一晩中
相手を寝かせませんですよ はい！
Bastard! What do you think you're
saying in front of my brother!?
貴様！ 兄者の前で何を言うか！
おめえ 何赤くなってんだ？
What are you blushing for?
ふん！
I have plenty of other things as well,
他にも色々ございますよ
from children's toys
お子様の遊び道具から
女を彩る装飾品まで
to ornaments for adorning the womenfolk.
Is that the extent of your business here?
用はそれだけか？
This area could erupt into
war at any moment.
ここは いつ戦場になってもおかしくない
If you stay here for too long,
you may become caught up in it.
長居をすれば巻き添えを食うことになる
It couldn't be!
そんなあ
でしたら どうして
あんな可愛い娘さん達がいるんです？
If that were the case, why are these
pretty young ladies here?
In any case, I cannot allow anyone not
involved to get wrapped up in this.
とにかく無関係な人間を
巻き込むわけにはいかない
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
はっ　はあ！ は はい！
Yes!
Give him some of our water and food.
この者に水と食料を分けてやってくれ
あ はい　すぐに
All right, I'll do it right away.
I apologize for any rudeness shown you.
Let me send you off.
仲間が失礼した
ご苦労
If you insist, I will leave.
旦那がそう仰るんであれば
出ていきますがね
But let me give you a warning.
では１つ
ご忠告を
What is that?
うん？ 何だ
If I were an assassin, I would
have taken your life.
私が刺客でしたら
あなたのお命頂戴しておりました
If you were an assassin, huh?
刺客ならば な
おっと 忘れるところでした
Oh, I almost forgot...
As a symbol of our friendship,
let me give you the hellapetter.
お近づきの印に ヘラペッタでございます
No, thank you, I do not really...
いや 私は別に
I wish I could have given you
some Mui Kowha.
できればムイコーハを
お分けできるとよかったのですが
Yes...
はい
どうぞ
Here you are. I'm afraid there isn't much.
少ししかありませんが
これはどうも お嬢さん
Why, thank you very much, young lady.
Well, I will take my leave now. Yes...
それでは私はこれで
はい
関の見張りとは
Guarding a checkpoint...
Man, we've sure been sent to the boondocks.
また ちんけな所に回されたもんだぜ
こんなんじゃ 体が
なまっちまう一方ですぜえ！
At this rate, my muscles are going to atrophy.
We being invaded!?
関破りか？
Don't let him get away!
逃がすなああー！
He went this way!
そっちへ行ったぞおー！
Be on your way.
ゆきなさい
ああ さっさと行けって言ってんだ！
Hurry up and go, will ya?
You find him?
いたかああー！
あー こっちにはいねえ！
Nah, there's no one here.
Let's check the other side.
向こうを捜すぞ
I have been waiting for you, Chikinaro.
待ってましたよ
チキナロ
My, my, I guess I can't fool you.
やれやれ あなた様の
目はごまかせませんか
それで いかがでした？
So, what did you find?
He is an extremely interesting individual.
なかなか面白いお方でした
For the details...
詳しい内容は こちらをご覧ください
Please have a look at this.
約束のものです
This is what I promised you.
I have taken receipt of it.
お代は確かに
Thank you for your continued
patronage! Yes!
毎度ありがとうございますです はい
それでは私はこれで
Then, I shall be on my way.
Then we head here... then here...
そんでえ こう来て
こう来てっとお
後ろがガラあきじゃあ
That will leave us wide open in the back.
We'll be slaughtered before we
get to Inkalla's castle.
それではインカラの
城に着く前に全滅じゃぞ
ああ 考えんのは苦手なんだよ
So I'm no good at strategizing.
What do you think, brother?
兄者 どう思う
We do not have a great enough force yet.
まだ力が足りない
Seems to me we've collected
quite a few people.
随分集まったと思うんだがなあ
This checkpoint is positioned so as
to prevent interchange.
この関が互いの交流を
妨げるように建てられている
この先の里と協力できれば
勝機があるのだが
If we can get the cooperation of
the villages beyond it,
there is a chance we can win.
I wonder how things are on their side?
あちら側も いったい
どうなっていることか
ハクオロさーん！
Hakuoro-san!
This man, he...
この人が…
I... I have come from beyond the checkpoint.
私は関の向こうから 来ました
えっ？ 何？
I see, so things are pretty bad
beyond the checkpoint too.
そうか
関向こうも ひでえことに…
The people of the villages all feel the same.
既に どの里も気持ちは１つです
We can no longer allow the Emperor
to do as he pleases.
これ以上 おかみの好き勝手に
させるわけにはいきません
Please, Hakuoro-sama...
どうか ハクオロ様！
Brother!
兄者！
We shall take the Tatokori checkpoint.
タトコリの関を落とす
We shall begin at sunrise tomorrow.
決行は明朝 日の出
Sorry I'm late.
遅くなってごめんなさい
It's okay.
いいえ
I'll have your medicine ready soon.
すぐにお薬を作りますね
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
It sounds different than usual.
いつもと違う音？
Say, how is Hakuoro-sama?
あの
ハクオロ様はどうしてますか？
He seems to be very busy.
すごく 忙しいみたいで…
Is that so?
そうですか
I don't get much of a chance to talk to him.
私も なかなかお話しできなくて
I guess it can't be helped.
Times are difficult now.
仕方ないですよね
大変な時なんですから
あは！
What's wrong?
どうした？ うおっ！
ぐっ ぐっ… あっ ああっ
Attack!
突っ込めええー！
何だー！
敵だー！
Don't open the gates! Are you trying
to let the enemy in!?
門を開けるな！
敵を中に入れる気か！
General!
大将おおー！
Let's go.
行きましょう
急げ！
Hurry!
Open up a breach for us!
突入口を広げるんだあー！
いっい や うっ うう！
Hurry!
急げ！
Oboro!
オボロ！
Okay!
おう！
あっ やあ！ せい！
ふぅーあ！ あう
Now's our chance! Break down the walls!
今のうちに壁を崩すぞおー！
えやっ！
ふん！
Benawi...
ベナウィ
What are you two doing here!?
何で貴様らが！
Looks like we're fated to meet.
縁があるじゃねえか
I guess it's not so bad that we got
transferred here after all.
ここに飛ばされたのも
まんざらじゃなかったようだぜ
Yeah...
Not bad at all!
まんざらじゃない！
Let's go.
行きます
About time!
待ってやした
Hold your formations! Don't let
the enemy get behind you!
隊形を崩すな！
敵を後ろへ回すんじゃねえぞ！
Don't stick together back here! Go!
固まるな！
展開！
I don't have time to waste on
small fry! Outta the way!
雑魚には用はねえ
どけええー！
へやっ！
しょうがねえ
Come on then! I'll take you on!
相手になってやるよ！
There you go!
そうこなくちゃあ
If you want to take down our leader,
you've got to stop me first.
大将をやりたきゃ 俺を止めてみせな
やああー！ ふっ ふっ！
うう！ １人で敵に向かうなあー！
Don't face the enemy alone!
Work in groups of at least two!
２人以上の組を作れえー！
ぬうっ
はは はっ！ ベナウィ
Benawi...
You seem surprised that my squad is here.
私の隊がいたことは
予想外だったようですね
Kid...
あんちゃん
Sonnuva bitch!
-この野郎おおー！ ふっ
-だめだ！
No!
Sonnuva bitch!
ぎぃ　ああ… つ 強ぇ…
He... He's strong...
うぅああー！
Please surrender.
降伏してください
At this rate, you will all be annihilated.
このままでは あなた方は
全滅してしまいますよ
I wonder about that.
それはどうかな
あっ ああ！ 何だ？
What's that?
Perfect timing!
ええ… ドンピシャだぜ
I see...
なるほど
Looks like you did not expect this.
予想外だったようだな
How did they...
どうやって
Honored brother!
兄者様！ んっ ふっ　うっ
Good job!
よくやった
This would not have been possible
without your speed.
お前達の足でなければ不可能だった
You mean you had them pass
through the forest?
森を抜けさせたというのですか
That was daring.
大胆な
But it was a sure bet.
しかし 確実だ
We will abandon this place.
ここを放棄します
You can't do that.
それはねえですぜえ
He's absolutely right!
全くだ
うおおおー！
うおおおー！ やったあー！
There is no need to go after them.
追う必要は無い
Our goal was to destroy this checkpoint.
我々の目的は関の破壊だ
But...
んん しかし　あいつらが
間に合わなかったらって思うと ヒヤッとするぜ
When I think what would have happened if
those two hadn't made it, I get the chills.
The conditions were set.
条件は揃っていた
I do not fight battles I stand
no chance of winning.
勝算のない戦はしない
Oh, is that right? I should have known!
そ そうか
さすが あんちゃんだ
だーはっはっはっはっ！
あっ て… いってぇ…
Ouch...
ああ！ あんた
Welcome home. You won, didn't you?
おかえり
勝ったんだね
Of course!
あったりめえよ
You called for me?
お呼びでしょうか
How can you come before me so brazenly!?
よーくも いけしゃあしゃあと！
I hear you couldn't even defend
one measly checkpoint
小さな関１つも守れず 尻尾を巻いて
逃げ帰ってきたそうにゃもなあ
and have come home with your
tail between your legs.
I was not strong enough.
我が力及ばず
I am very disappointed in you.
おみゃあにゃあ失望したにゃも
While you were wasting your time,
Nuwangi took control of Chenma.
おみゃあが ちんたらしてる間に
ヌワンギはチェンマを制圧したにゃも
Chenma?
チェンマ？
But isn't that a settlement that
didn't join in the rebellion?
あそこは反乱には加わっていない
集落ではありませんか
One must nip a disaster in the bud,
before it has a chance to develop!
災いの芽は小さいうちに摘むにゃもよ
ぷーぷぷぷぷ！
Your Highness...
聖上 理解しておいでですか？
Do you understand what this means?
What?
にゃーも？
Do you understand what you have done!?
ご自分のしたことを理解しておいでか
Wh.. What!?
んにゃっ にゃっ んっ… 皇（オゥルォ）は
何をしたっていいんだにゃも！
An emperor can do whatever he pleases!
No!
否！
The foundation of a country is its people.
國の基盤は民
Without its people, a country does not exist!
民無くして國は無い！
If you ignore the people, how can
your country have a future?
民をないがしろにして
どうして國に あすがありましょう！
General!
大将
ぐっ おみゃあ！
Why, you... you!
おみゃあが　お おみゃあが
つっ つけ上がるにゃも！
You! Who do you think you are?
I have tolerated you because of your
distinguished military service.
今ま… 今まで おみゃあの武勲に免じて
大目に見てやっていたにゃもがあ
ひいっ　もう我慢ならーん！ ひいぃ
But I can't take it any longer.
You're right!
そうだぜ
Huh?
I was listening. You ingrate!
聞いてたぞ この恩知らずが！
Uncle, it's no use trying to talk to this guy.
おじき
こんな奴に何を言っても無駄なだけだぜ
Oh, Nuwangi!
ぬおおっ ヌワンギ
Just leave the rest up to me.
Don't worry about a thing.
後は俺に任せて
安心して くつろいでいてくれ
にゃぷうー ふっ
ぷううー ぶはあー
This is the end of you.
てめえはもう 終わりだ
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
Invasion of the Imperial City